+506 83269311 ☐
hello@joseavila.design ☐
joseavila.design ☐

6 months

2016 - 2017

1.5 years

Jose Antonio Avila Paniagua

Interaction Designer

Profile

Versatile Interaction Designer with an Industrial Design Engineering background and more than 9 years of experience as a UX/UI designer. My creative side brings ideas with strong communication skills, and my inner engineer loves finding solutions to everyday problems.

Experience

| 2023 | Senior UX Designer at Publicis Sapient — Costa Rica |
|----------------|--|
| July – present | Lead UX strategy, research, and design initiatives by prototyping high fidelity solutions to shape how clients serve their customers. |
| 2022 — 2023 | Interaction Design Senior Analyst at Accenture — Costa Rica |
| 1 year | Analyze complex assets used in the development of digital interfaces based on user experience and best practices to generate digital products. |
| 2021 | Senior UX at Prodigious — Costa Rica |
| 6 months | Responsible for UX, creative design and user-centered design of software in coordination with other creative, marketing and development teams. |
| 2019 — 2021 | UX Designer at Hangar — Costa Rica |
| 1.5 years | Understanding users, costumers, and clients to create UX opportunities and propose solutions that contribute with digital products. |
| 2019 | Interaction Designer at 17K — Stuttgart, Germany |
| 9 months | Taking part in the ideation and creation of interactive installations and interfaces along with generative design and projection mapping. |
| 2018 — 2019 | UX Designer at Qanta Media — Costa Rica |

Interaction & Experience Design projects creating immersive digital

User Interface and Mobile Application Design in iOS & Android. Direct contact

experiences, applying new technologies to marketing.

with clients during the design and developing process.

UI/UX Designer at Symbiotic — Costa Rica

+506 83269311 hello@joseavila.design joseavila.design

Education

2021 - 2022Copenhagen Institute of Interaction Design — Denmark

Graduated with Honors from Interaction Design programme (Graduate School).

2017 - 2018HfG Schwäbisch Gmünd — Germany

One-year exchange student.

2012 - 2019Instituto Tecnológico de Costa Rica — Costa Rica

Bachelor in Industrial Design Engineering.

2007 - 2011EMVA High School — Costa Rica

High School Diploma. Studied in bilingual school since 2001.

Skills

Design User Experience Design thinking Visual Interface Design User Centered Design

Research Prototyping

Software Adobe Illustrator Sketch

Adobe Photoshop Framer Adobe After Effects Figma Adobe InDesign Principle Adobe XD inVision

Programming Arduino HTML

CSS Processing

Soft skills Communication skills Adaptability

> Teamwork Creativity

Language Spanish - Native proficiency

English - Professional proficiency

German - A2 Level